<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-07T17:06:24-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/</id><title type="html">Chancoin</title><subtitle>News from the \'tistic underbelly of crypto.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Nightcap Has Arrived</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/07/Nightcap_is_Live.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nightcap Has Arrived" /><published>2018-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/07/Nightcap_is_Live</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/07/Nightcap_is_Live.html">&lt;p&gt;After much weeping and gnashing of teeth, the 0.15 update is finally complete. Just check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://chan.cryptocronic.com/stats/&quot;&gt;these stats&lt;/a&gt; on how smoothly the chain is operating - ‘tis beauty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I go into the specifics of what 0.15 brings us, however - I have to say thank you to a few folks without whom this could never have happened. Name 1856 wrote and implemented Nightcap (formerly called Cloverhash), however we wouldn’t have made it this far without significant assistance from Barry, Metagame and Mangofusion.
More generally, I have to thank the entire ChanCoin community - I’ve learned a great deal in the past few months, mostly about the intangiable aspects of running a project as unique as Chancoin. I’ve said in the past that one’s progress in all worthwhile endeavors is proprotional to one’s willingness to fail repeatedly, and the 0.15 rollout was no exception - mistakes were made and lessons were learned all around, and we’re all better for it. I look forward to continuing this trajectory - it’s been an honor being given the support of the community and the opportunity to grow alongside this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goals with 0.15 were twofold: firstly to improve the stability of the blockchain itself and secondly to give us the tools needed to start looking at some really fun, interesting applications for Chancoin. We’ve absolutely achieved the first, and exploring the second is going to be some of the most fun items on the team’s radar for 2018. There’s still a lot fo fundamental work left to be done, of course - GPU Nightcap mining is available but still developing at breakneck speed, so expect lots of developments there - but some of the next items on our radar are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website Redesign &amp;amp; Updated Roadmap - We’ve got a truly awesome designer lined up for this and hope to have the new website done in late April to early May&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile Wallet - Community member Jabo is working on a mobile walet for both Android and iOS. While this is not an official project, we’re supporting him logistically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White Paper - Nightcap needs documenting. I look forward to working with Name on this one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin 2.0 Support - Now that our blockchain can support it, we can get down to implementing tools for digital asset applications in earnest!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More Exchanges - We’re working with some great community members to bring CHAN to new exchanges. We want to favor quality over quantity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you want to get in touch, the best way is by dropping into our &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.me/chancoin&quot;&gt;official discord&lt;/a&gt; and having a chat - or by posing a question in our BCT &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=2152411.0&quot;&gt;ANN thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks as always for your continued support,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gossamer Socks&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gossamer Socks</name></author><summary type="html">After much weeping and gnashing of teeth, the 0.15 update is finally complete. Just check out these stats on how smoothly the chain is operating - ‘tis beauty!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Merry Christmas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/25/merry_christmas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Merry Christmas" /><published>2017-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/25/merry_christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/25/merry_christmas.html">&lt;p&gt;Christmas is over for pretty much everyone except us here in Burgerland, but I wanted to be sure to get this out before the official end of the holiday - a few words of gratitude for those who’ve helped support the project and a few more about where we’ll be going in the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier today, when asked about how things are going with the project, I responded by paraphrasing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gurren_Lagann#Conflicts&quot;&gt;Takami Akai&lt;/a&gt;: I said that running a crypto project is like having an anus six inches from your face at all times, doing what anuses do best. Akai was speaking about the childishness of 2ch; I’m obliquely referencing the craven idiocy of [parts of] 4chan, particularly /biz/. For the past six months I’ve been harangued - in cyber- and meatspace - by craven and simpleminded individuals who seem to feel both deeply entitled to be at or near the center of this project and deeply offended that their attempts to hijack and/or micromanage our team were unwelcome. I take this as a sign that we’re doing something very right - imitation combined with autistic screeching truly is the sincerest form of flattery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that this project has been massively stress-inducing, I’ve gained a great deal from it as well - and I don’t mean financially. Our community has some very smart, kind and clever people from all over the world - I’m one of only a handful of Americans on the discord server - and their company has enriched my life incalculably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has also been ample opportunity to learn - on many levels. Failure precedes success in &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; worthwhile endeavor, and it &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; precedes a worthwhile lesson learned or intuitive understanding of useful knowledge. I’ll happily admit that I’ve failed many times since I joined this project and that at best only half of those failures have resulted in a boon - whether technical knowledge, wisdom in working with others, or thicker skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s the part where I get to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m incalculably grateful because for every one of those failures which have made me smarter, stronger or more capable at least one of our community members has been instrumental in making it happen. There are too many to name here, of course. I’m also excited for the next opportunity to fail - and to transmute that failure into knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of this would be possible without a great community of patient, kind, intelligent and very creative people - thanks to you all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I wrap up, I’ll say a few words about where we’re headed in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our wallet dev Name and I are working closely to get all tests on our 0.15 branch passing. We’ve been conducting some manual regression and integration testing as well, however getting all tests green is really the next logical step to being &lt;em&gt;confident&lt;/em&gt; that the release has no glaring issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This takes time - especially for volunteer devs who have full time jobs and/or school. We’ve got some new teammates (Mango and Bitwise, I’m looking at you) who are helping us where possible, but they too have work and school to contend with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to commit to a release window for 0.15 - we said we wanted to get a Release Candidate out before the year’s end, and we’re still working to do that. This statement alone has been misconstrued as some kind of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wow Release Date Available In Stores&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as if we were shipping a new version of Windows or Call of Duty. In order to avoid causing yet &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; conniptions on the part of our detractors, we won’t even make futher statements of this kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we’ll say from now on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’ll be ready when its ready.
If you want to help, make a PR. The code is open source.
If you want to complain or harangue us, piss off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas!
Gossamer Socks&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gossamer Socks</name></author><summary type="html">Christmas is over for pretty much everyone except us here in Burgerland, but I wanted to be sure to get this out before the official end of the holiday - a few words of gratitude for those who’ve helped support the project and a few more about where we’ll be going in the next few months.</summary></entry></feed>